

Name Per Lövdinger Phone 0739023436

Email per.lovdinger@gmail.com

Linkedin <u>Link</u>

Address Kalibervägen 1,43350 Öjersjö

Pers.no 600702-0255



## **Work Overview**

Professional and dedicated Java Solution Architect with the ability to meet and fulfill client's business goals. Experience in the requirements of commercial IT-development, and capable of participating in many team roles. He has extensive experience in Java Enterprise technologies and object-oriented methods and has worked 3 years as self employed Java-Consultant in Dublin, Ireland. Easy co-worker and positive attitude.

Recently assignment experiences:

- Lead Architect TCP-Test Management Volvo Group Trucks Technology
- Lead Architect Gloria Volvo Group Trucks Technology
- Software Architect / Team Lead SCM Volvo Parts
- Software Architect Volvo 3P
- Senior Java Developer SID Volvo Parts
- Solution Architect CDB Volvo Cars
- Application Architect W2VCC Volvo Cars
- Designer/Developer J2EE applications Volvo Parts
- Designer proof-of-concept architecture, NG Next Generation, Volvo Cars
- Java-Mentor Volvo Cars IT, Torslanda
- Senior Software Engineer Omnipay, Dublin
- Team-leader Marrakech, Dublin

## **Business Experience:**

Automotive, Logistics, Bank industry, Credit card industry, Ecommerce

#### Roles:

Lead Architect, IT Architect, Team Lead, Designer, Developer, Mentor

## Languages:

Swedish, English German, French

## **Education:**

Gothenburg University, Information Technology 1984-1986

## **Employment History**

| Company                | Title                              | Period    |
|------------------------|------------------------------------|-----------|
| Volvo IT, Gothenburg   | IT Architect                       | 2002 -    |
| Self employed, Ireland | Java Consultant                    | 1999-2002 |
| Volvo IT, Gothenburg   | Method specialist                  | 1994-1999 |
| Volvo Logistics        | Analyst, Developer, Project leader | 1986-1994 |



## **Assignment History**

Customer: Volvo Group Trucks Technology

Assignment/Project: TCP Test Management

Role Lead Architect

Method/Techniques Rich Web Client, Java script framework (Angular, TypeScript),

RESTful Services, Java EE 6 (JPA,JMS) ,Spring, XML-schema, JAXB, Volvo Frameworks (JVS) , Database PostgreSQL, JBOSS, Eclipse, Maven,GIT

Description of Assignment: Lead Architect for new global application that supports the Test

management process of complete vehicle

Duration: October 2016-present

Customer: Volvo Group Trucks Technology

Assignment/Project DVP prestudies
Role Lead Architect
Method/Techniques not applicable

Description of Assignments: PLM Services Roadmap

Strategy for development tools for Embedded Software Engineering

Duration: August 2016 – October 2016

Customer: Volvo Group Trucks Technology

Assignment/Project: Gloria

Role Lead Architect

Method/Techniques Rich Web Client, RESTful Services, Java EE 5

 $(Servlet,\!EJB,\!JPA,\!JMS)\;,\;XML\text{-schema},\;\;JAXB$ 

Volvo Frameworks (JVS3), Databases (PostgreSQL,Derby) Eclipse, Subversion, Websphere Application Server,tomcat

Description of Assignment: Lead Architect for new global application that supports Procurement,

Order, Delivery Control and Storage of parts in Prototype warehouses. Application supports GTT global process "Build

Physical Object".

Duration: April 2012 – June 2016

Customer: Volvo Group Trucks Technology

Assignment/Project Protus TOM
Role Senior Developer

Method/Techniques Java EE 5 (Servlet, EJB, JPA, JMS), XML-schema, JAXB

Volvo Frameworks (JVS3, Java Swing), Databases (DB2,Derby)

Eclipse 3.6 Galileo, subversion

Description of Assignment: Develop a domain oriented solution for PROTUS Test Object

Management.

Duration: October 2011 – April 2012

Customer
Assignment/Project
Role
Volvo Parts
SCM DM R3
Architect/Team lead

Method/Techniques Java EE 5 (Servlet,EJB,JPA,JMS), XML-schema, JAXB

Volvo Frameworks (JVS3, VPLF), Databases (DB2,Derby)

Eclipse 3.6 Galileo, subversion

Description of Assignment: Architect/Team lead for development of new global DFS (Dealer

facing system) which will be used by Volvo, Renault and Mack.

Leading a team of 11 developers.

Duration January 2010 – October 2011



**Customer:** Volvo 3P

Assignment/Project **KOLA Integration roadmap** 

Role Architect Method/Techniques: not applicable

Developing and documenting new Kola integration strategy. Description of Assignment:

Coordinate pilot-test of KOLA Integration with 3P platform.

October 2009 – December 2009 Duration:

**Customer:** Volvo Parts

**SID** – Service Information Database Assignment/Project

Senior Java developer Role

Rational Application Developer 7.0, WebSphere-6.1, Method:

J2EE 1.4, J2SE5.0, Web Services, EJB, DB2, MQ, JMS, XSD,

Scrum, Clearcase

SID – SGML2XML project. Description of Assignment:

Designed and implemented various tasks in the project.

January 2009 – October 2009 Duration:

**Customer:** Volvo Cars

Assignment/Project **CDB** – Customer DataBase

Role Solution Architect

Method: Rational Application Developer 7.0, WebSphere-6.1,

J2EE 1.4, J2SE5.0, Web Services, EJB, JSP, Struts, Oracle, MQ, JMS, XSD ,JAXB, OAGIS, test-driven development, ant, cruise-

control, UML, Subversion

CDB is an application that serves as the consumer master at Description of Assignment:

VCC and is integrated with many different systems, e.g. ordering, warranty, prospect and sales lead, soft product,

customer complaint. My role as solution architect consisted of being

responsible for the application architecture, the design, the

integrations and the infrastructure. October 2007 – December 2008

**Customer: Volvo Cars** Assignment/Project

W2VCC project

Application architect – team lead Role

TP2007:J2EE 1.4, J2SE5.0, Rational Application Developer 7.0, Method: WebSphere, 6.1 test-driven development, ant, cruise-control,

Oracle, DB2, MQSeries, Ehub and CVS

Integration project to enable communication between KDP and Description of Assignment

WERS.

Establishing IT-architecture and design of a new J2EE-application **Duration:** 

called Translator that serves as an integration-application. Team lead

and responsible for the development of the application.

November 2006 – October 2007

**Customer:** Volvo Parts Assignment/Project IMPACT 3.0

Role Developer/Designer J2EE

Method: J2EE 1.4, Rational Application Developer, WebSphere, test-driven

development, ANT, cruise-control, Oracle

Description of Assignment:

Duration:

J2EE/Web Application that provides that quick access to latest parts,

service information and vehicle specification.

Designing and developing Impact 3.0.

September 2005 – November 2006 Duration:



Customer: Volvo Parts

Assignment/Project SID 4.2 - Service Information Database

Role Developer/Designer J2EE

Method: J2EE 1.3, WSAD, WebSphere, test-driven development, ANT

Jeeves, WebServices, Castor, DB2

Description of Assignment: Designing and developing SID 4.2.

Duration: March 2005 - September 2005

Customer: Volvo Cars

Assignment/Project NG – Next Generation - Architecture proof-of-concept

Role Designer/Developer/Architect

Method: J2EE, USDM, WSAD, WebSphere, test-driven development, ant,

maven, Oracle

Description: NG will support a VCC global solution for products in

process(PPS) and material planning systems.

Designing proof-of-concept architecture – establishing guidelines for

design.

Duration: October-2004 - March 2005

Customer: Volvo Cars Torslanda – IT department

Assignment/Project Various project for example OEE

Role Java Mentor

Method: Websphere, J2EE, EJB (incl. Message Driven Beans),

Servlet, JSP, Struts, JMS, ant, Tenvironment, VMS, Mimer

Description of Assignment: Method/Technique support for Java-projects within the VCT-IT

organisation.

Duration: October 2002 – October 2004

Customer: Omnipay, Dublin www.omnipaygroup.com

Assignment/Project RAM – project. Omnipay provides and develops a service for

creditcard-transactions over the internet.

Role Software Architect, designer

Method: J2EE, EJB, JSP, Oracle, WebLogic

Description of Assignment: Created the architecture, designed and implemented a proof-of-

concept solution for Omnipay Ram-Web-application.

We used Weblogic as the application-server, Java Server Pages as

client technology and EJB as the back-end technology.

The contract has also involved administration of Weblogic servers. I have also designed and implemented a file-transmission system

involving XML-technology (DOM/SAX).

Duration: December 2000-October 2002



Customer: Marrakech, Dublin www.marrakech.com

Assignment/Project Laser – Marrakech
Role Team-leader, Developer
Method: Netdynamics, Java, Web, EJB

Description of Assignment: During this period I worked on an E-commerce project developing a

web-application for procurement. We used Netdynamics as

application-server and technologies such as Java 1.2, Enterprise Java

Beans, Web and HTML.

During the last 6 months I worked as the Lead Engineer/Team Lead

developing a new release of the eProcurement application.

I was responsible for Technical Design and managed a team of 10

engineers implementing the software.

Duration: October 1999- December 2000

Customer: Bank of Ireland, Dublin www.bankofireland.com

Assignment/Project CEB-project – Bank of Ireland

Role Developer Method: Cool:Gen

Description of Assignment: Worked on contract basis for the CEB-project (Commercial

Electronic Banking) at Bank of Ireland, developing back-end

applications using a case-tool called Cool:Gen.

Duration: July 1999 - October 1999

Customer: Volvo

Assignment/Project Various java-projects

Role Java Mentor

Method: Websphere, Java, Web, Servlet, EJB, Applet

Description of Assignment: I worked as a member of a Java-team where we gave support to Java-

projects within Volvo.

From the beginning of 1999, I was promoted to a position as a Java

Method leader.

The position meant that I was responsible for: The communication of information regarding Java Coordinating of Java-activities within Volvo

Exchanging experiences between Java-projects at Volvo Suggesting strategies/architecture for Java-projects

Duration: July 1998 - July 1999



# Training

| Date | Training                             | Comment | Institute/Supplier |
|------|--------------------------------------|---------|--------------------|
| 2017 | Enterprise Architecture Repository   |         |                    |
| 2013 | JVS - In depth training              |         |                    |
| 2013 | Introduction to Websphere MQ         |         |                    |
| 2013 | BlackBelt-Volvo Group Software       |         |                    |
|      | Architecture Course                  |         |                    |
| 2012 | Teamleader                           |         |                    |
| 2012 | PMTP D2 - Soft Skills Fundamentals   |         |                    |
| 2012 | ITA Training – Integration           |         |                    |
| 2011 | JVS                                  |         |                    |
| 2011 | ITA training module I&O              |         |                    |
| 2008 | Black belt 2008                      |         |                    |
| 2006 | Advanced Object Orientation with UML |         | Informator         |
| 2004 | IT Architect – Certification program |         | Dataföreningen     |
| 1999 | Enterprise Java Beans                |         |                    |
| 1998 | Rational Rose – RUP                  |         |                    |
| 1997 | Corba – basics                       |         | Rational           |
| 1997 | Java Basics                          |         |                    |